<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr Rebecca McElroy</title>
    <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr Rebecca McElroy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2025 </copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/about_me/</guid>
      <description>Hello!!
I am a Research Fellow in the Centre for Astrophysics at the University of Southern Queensland. I am based, however, in Sydney where I hold honorary appointments at the University of Sydney and Macquarie University. Throughout the week you can usually find me at SIfA on Mondays, Macquarie on Fridays, and working from home the rest of the week. I&amp;rsquo;m usually on UniSQ campus once a month, so if you need to see me in person just let me know and we can coordinate.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/about_me/featured_old.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/art_about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/art_about/</guid>
      <description>Art has been a lifelong hobby of mine. I have always loved to draw and paint. Recently I have been drawing astronomical observatories, some of which are shown above. Want a drawing of your telescope? Shoot me an email or a DM on instagram or twitter.
I also do a lot of portaiture of characters from TV and video games, and make stickers on redbubble.
On this site you can find my telescope illustrations and other science illustration scribbles, which are free for you to use with attribution.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/art_about/featured.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/meal_deals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/meal_deals/</guid>
      <description>Love a good meal deal? Live in Brisbane? Me too!
Check out my (WIP) list of current lunch and dinner deals in central Brisbane. Click here to view or request edit access if you want to contribute.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/outreach/</guid>
      <description>Need an astronomy expert? I do frequent outreach work in schools, pubs, on the radio, and occasionally even on TV.
Shoot me an email or reach out on Bluesky or LinkedIn and we can see what we can organise. I also have several fantastic students who love outreach and would love to be involved.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/sci_art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/sci_art/</guid>
      <description>Science illustration combines my two passions. I started out doing simple drawings for talks and have recently been illustrating astronomical observatories. You can find my work on instagram, twitter, and even redbubble if you would like a sticker or mug.
On this site you can find my various illustrations, which are free for you to use with attribution. Enjoy!</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/sci_art/featured.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/study_unisq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/study_unisq/</guid>
      <description>Interested in studying Astronomy, Astrophysics, or Space Science? UniSQ is home to Queensland&amp;rsquo;s only professional observatory and the iLaunch programme, a collaboration of three universities and 20+ industry partners to boost Australia’s sovereign space capability.
Our world-class academics study astronomical objects from comets to quasars. In addition to hosting one of Australia&amp;rsquo;s largest exoplanet groups, we have scientists working on solar system objects, stars, galaxies, and black holes. I lead an extragalactic and active galaxies research group at UniSQ.</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/study_unisq/featured.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/useful_links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/useful_links/</guid>
      <description>Here I&amp;rsquo;ve collated useful links that may come in handy.
Finding papers:
NASA Astronomical Data System - a search engine for finding papers arxiv - open access repository for the latest astronomy papers, beware - some of these mightn&amp;rsquo;t have been refereed yet! Dawes reviews - a series of papers reviewing topical areas of astronomy comissioned by the Publications of the Astronomical Society of Australia. Galaxies:
Emission line list - what&amp;rsquo;s that line?</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galaxies @ UniSQ</title>
      <link>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rebeccamcelroy.github.io/group/</guid>
      <description>Dr Rebecca McElroyGroup LeadLeads the Close AGN Reference Survey (CARS) investigating the physics of nearby active galaxies. Co-chair of the LSST AGN Science Collaboration’s Watchlist and Follow-up Working Groups, and member of the HECTOR team - an Australian next-generation integral-field spectrograph for galaxy evolution studies.
Email Thomas DunnHonours StudentCombining archival photographic plates with contemporary multi-wavelength observations to build a century-long light curve of the changing-look active galaxies Mrk 1018. His work bridges historical datasets with modern time-domain astronomy to trace accretion-rate evolution over decades.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
